[
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "Which type of economy does India have?",
        "answer": "Mixed",
        "choices": [
            "Mixed",
            "Socialist",
            "Gandhian",
            "Free"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "The main source of national income of India is",
        "answer": "Service",
        "choices": [
            "Service",
            "Manufacturing",
            "Agriculture",
            "Foreign Remittances"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "As the economy develops, the national income share of tertiary sector",
        "answer": "goes on increasing",
        "choices": [
            "goes on increasing",
            "first decreases, then increase",
            "first increase, then decrease",
            "goes on decreasing"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "One of the problems in calculating National Income in India is",
        "answer": "non-organised sector",
        "choices": [
            "non-organised sector",
            "under-employment",
            "inflation",
            "low level of savings"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "Which of the following is not a method to calculate the Gross Domestic Product (GDP)?",
        "answer": "Diminishing Cost Method",
        "choices": [
            "Diminishing Cost Method",
            "Product Method",
            "Income Method",
            "Expenditure Method"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "Which one does not come under economic infrastructure?",
        "answer": "Education or Health",
        "choices": [
            "Education or Health",
            "Energy",
            "Roads",
            "Railway"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "Hindu growth is related to",
        "answer": "GDP",
        "choices": [
            "GDP",
            "Money",
            "Population",
            "GNP"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "What is money?",
        "answer": "Commodity",
        "choices": [
            "Commodity",
            "Income",
            "Wealth",
            "Savings"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "The economist who for the first time scientifically determined National Income in India?",
        "answer": "V K R V Rao",
        "choices": [
            "V K R V Rao",
            "D R Gadgil",
            "Manmohan Singh",
            "Y V Alagh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "Who was the remarkable person who took the action for calculating the national income of India before Independence?",
        "answer": "Dadabhai Naoroji",
        "choices": [
            "Dadabhai Naoroji",
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Surendranath Banerjee"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "Which of the following offices or institutes releases data of the National Income in India?",
        "answer": "Nationa Statistical Office (NSO)",
        "choices": [
            "Nationa Statistical Office (NSO)",
            "National Sample Survey Office (NSSO)",
            "Central Statistical Office (CSO) ",
            "NITI Ayog"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "Which organisation carries out the survey for determining the poverty line?",
        "answer": "Nationa Statistical Office (NSO)",
        "choices": [
            "Nationa Statistical Office (NSO)",
            "National Sample Survey Office (NSSO)",
            "Reserve Bank of India (RBI)",
            "NITI Ayog"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "Which ministry is responsible for calculating GDP of India?",
        "answer": "Ministry of Central Statistical and Program Implementation",
        "choices": [
            "Ministry of Central Statistical and Program Implementation",
            "Ministry of Commerce and Industry",
            "Ministry of Finance",
            "Ministry of Consumer Affairs"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "The best index of economic income can be provided by",
        "answer": "increase in per capita real income per year",
        "choices": [
            "increase in per capita real income per year",
            "increase in national income at current price",
            "increase in savings ration",
            "improvement in balance of payment position"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "Per Capita income of a country is obtained from",
        "answer": "both National Income and Population",
        "choices": [
            "both National Income and Population",
            "Population",
            "National Income",
            "GDP"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "The latest per capita income at constant prices is lowest for which state of India?",
        "answer": "Bihar",
        "choices": [
            "Bihar",
            "Uttar Pradesh",
            "Jharkhand",
            "Manipur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "The latest per capita income at constant prices is highest for which state of India?",
        "answer": "Sikkim",
        "choices": [
            "Sikkim",
            "Goa",
            "Telangana",
            "Karnataka"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "Which state of India has highest Gross State Domestic Product (GSDP)?",
        "answer": "Maharashtra",
        "choices": [
            "Maharashtra",
            "Karnataka",
            "Uttar Pradesh",
            "Tamil Nadu"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "Which sector of Indian economy contributes the most to the Gross National Product (GNP)?",
        "answer": "Tertiary Sector",
        "choices": [
            "Tertiary Sector",
            "Secondary Sector",
            "Primary Sector",
            "Public Sector"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "Which organization publishes the global Sustainable Development Report (SDR)?",
        "answer": "UN Sustainable Development Solutions Network",
        "choices": [
            "UN Sustainable Development Solutions Network",
            "NITI Aayog",
            "United Nations Development Programme (UNDP)",
            "World Bank"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "As per the Sustainable Development Report (SDR) 2025, what is India's rank in the SDG Index out of 167 countries?",
        "answer": "99th",
        "choices": [
            "99th",
            "109th ",
            "112th",
            "121st"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "Which Indian organization is responsible for monitoring the progress of SDGs at the sub-national level (States and UTs)?",
        "answer": "NITI Aayog",
        "choices": [
            "NITI Aayog",
            "Ministry of Finance",
            "Reserve Bank of India (RBI)",
            "Ministry of Statistics and Programme Implementation (MoSPI)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "The SDG Index measures a country's progress towards which set of goals?",
        "answer": "17 goals",
        "choices": [
            "17 goals",
            "10 goals",
            "15 goals",
            "20 goals"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "The Human Capital Index (HCI) is published by which of the following international organizations?",
        "answer": "World Bank",
        "choices": [
            "World Bank",
            "United Nations Development Programme (UNDP)",
            "World Health Organisation (WHO)",
            "International Monetary Fund (IMF)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Economy",
        "question": "In India, the agricultural crop year period is",
        "answer": "1st July to 30th June",
        "choices": [
            "1st July to 30th June",
            "1st June to 31st May",
            "1st April to 31st March",
            "1st January to 31st December"
        ]
    }
]